## **Anil Vasista**

Transformation Lead for an Insurance Company at Accenture in India

## Summary

Graduated in Electronics and Communication Engineering in 1992, joined Glowtronics Limited as Quality Assurance and Product engineer. Trained under Judy Bamberger in Software Engineering, transition from non-IT to IT industry. Worked with Sunlet Systems as Process and Quality Engineer. Driven by entrepreneurial interests, worked with Crescent Solutions and Multitude Methodologies. In December 2004, joined Accenture in India as a Software Quality Assurance engineer.

In 2 decades of working in the IT industry, have successfully worked with teams across geographies on Organization level initiatives. Exposed to diverse work culture in the geographies like Europe (United Kingdom, Ireland) and, Middle East (Kingdom of Saudi Arabia).

Over the last 12 years in the phenomenon that I mean Accenture, designed/ managed and delivered Quality Assurance/ Delivery Excellence/ Process Re-engineering Programs, Audit functions, Industrialization Programs, QA-PMO-Ops & Global Productivity Bench-marking, for the internal and external organizations. Registered Assessment Team Member (ATM) for CMMI assessments. ACN Certified Account Information Security Lead. Experienced Internal Auditor and Management Representative (MR) for ISO 9001, used to be on roasters of CSQA & CSTE professionals and ITIL v2 foundation certified.

Acquired Bachelors in Engineering in Electronics & Telecommunications (1992) and Masters in Engineering Management (1997), from University of Mysore.

## Experience

### Transformation Lead for an Insurance Company at Accenture in India

June 2016 - Present (10 months)

This insurance client used to operate in 3 major geographical regions. It has now embarked upon a journey to transform itself into a One global company.

We are aligning with clients business and in this transformation journey, I lead the Quality Assurance and Operating Model work streams and look into implementation of tools and assets to serve the client in the NEW IT.

Formulated E2E Operating Model, interacting with SMEs, Delivery Leads and project people. Currently leading implementation of company's very aspiring liquid platform, expecting to change the way IT projects are managed.

## Quality Assurance and Enablement Lead at Technology Center of Excellence, Accenture Saudi Arabia Limited

April 2015 - May 2016 (1 year 2 months)

Responsible to set up the Quality Management System (QMS) and Delivery Management processes, for the up coming Technology Center of Excellence (Tech CoE) at Al-Khobar, KSA.

Provide SME support to client's Quality Management Initiative, to streamline their Enterprise QMS and EPM to align with ISO 9001:2008.

Support Delivery Lead in managing Client Expectations

Responsible for QA & Delivery Excellence reviews

Responsible for Quality Certifications for Tech CoE

Capability build and resource development, through technology training coordinating with Delivery Lead.

Conducted Fundamentals, Delivery and Quality process training through technology academies.

Communications management in the Tech CoE.

Led 2 testing projects for ARAMCO.

#### Quality Operations and PMO Lead for a CMT Client at Accenture in India

February 2014 - May 2015 (1 year 4 months)

Responsible for stage gate review preparation from offshore perspective.

Build and develop an offshore team to support project management, quality management and resource management for Global operations.

Focus on Continuous Improvement initiatives for the existing processes and focus on implementation of planned initiatives.

Based on the past performance data, define SLAs for different activities performed by the team.

Responsible for setting up a governance structure for the team's operations.

Demonstrate increase in efficiency and productivity of the team at IDC, on a quarterly basis.

Responsible for follow up of Risks and Issues in the engagement.

# Innovation and Industrilization Program - Productivity Bench marking Lead at Accenture UK October 2011 - January 2014 (2 years 4 months)

Manage Productivity Bench marking with external vendors to position Accenture Productivity Performance against Industry standards. Level of interaction was with Technology Leadership, engagement leadership for program design and practitioners across Geographies and Delivery Centers, for implementation.

Expected to identify and manage vendor, design productivity measurement program and roll out, data collection and analysis, support estimator calibration and design tool for computing productivity across AD, AM and Testing work.

Articulate and present the industry bench marking results, for Accenture Senior Management.

Evolved and documented Standard approach to compute productivity improvement that is technology and entity agnostic.

Software Quality Assurance, Delivery Excellence, Process and Audit Consultant at Accenture in India

#### December 2004 - October 2011 (6 years 11 months)

Responsible for follow up of Risks and Issues in the engagement, plan and participate in stage gate reviews with the client senior management.

Defined High Maturity Processes in consultations with SMEs and CMMI framework to upgrade ADM from Level3 compliance to Level5 compliance.

Provided logistics support and facilitated the CMMI v1.3 appraisal operations starting with the pre-appraisal till the close of the appraisal. For the first time this was executed with dual appraisers.

Led a strong 10 member SQA team to support large Bank in US engagement, of around 1200 FTEs spread across 5 engagements and 42 projects. Defined and implemented requirement trace-ability audit process.

Defined basic Defect Management System for in house software development for a banking conglomerate, Ireland.

Defined, implemented and tracked quality processes during the build phase of CC&B for Australian Telecom company.

Facilitated QA reviews, Security Reviews, CMMI appraisals and Internal Quality audits.

#### **Principal Consultant at Crescent Solutions**

January 2001 - December 2004 (4 years)

Responsible for implementing QA, Training and Software engineering processes for the company by standardizing development, documentation, testing, change & release management and delivery processes.

Responsible for over-viewing manual and automated testing activities, using Mercury WinRunner and Rational Unified Process (RUP)

Responsible for mapping and analyzing the business and functional processes @ Mysore City Corporation (MCC).

Presented concepts and proposals for computerization of City Corporation to Director, KUIDFC and Corporation Commissioner, Chairman UDA, and MATF. Presentation and the proposal were well appreciated.

Conceptualized and coordinated designing a CRM application for a limited company in Mysore. The application is web enabled and integrated with their existing ERP system.

Conceptualized, coordinated and tested software services for HR Management, pharmaceutical retailers, jewel merchants, industrial inventory management, material resource planning and maintenance.

#### Process Engineer at Sunlet Systems (P) Limited

November 1999 - November 2001 (2 years 1 month)

Sunlet Inc., was a Oregon, USA based software development company catering to the cargo industry and real estate agencies. Sunlet had an offshore R&D center at Bangalore called Sunlet Systems (P) Ltd., The team here was involved in process re-engineering, development of a frame work for software developers called Sunlet Software Engineering Processes (SSEP).

Was Process Engineer, & Standard's coordinator responsible for:

- Software Engineering Process Definition
- Standards' Co-ordination
- Functional & Performance Testing of tools developed within Sunlet. These tools were parts of a suite that could be used by software development companies aimed at scaling different levels of CMM.
- Define Engineering Process- Sunlet Software Engineering Process (SSEP), aligned to CMM framework and IEEE Standards
- Training Team Members on SSEP

#### Quality Assurance and Production Manager at Glowtronics Limited

May 1993 - October 1999 (6 years 6 months)

As Manager (Manufacturing and Operations), Internal Auditor for ISO 9000, and Management Representative (MR), Asst.Manager (Production), Engineer (QC):

- MR for ISO 9000 Quality Assurance Model implemented in the organization
- Was a reviewed for certification audit and re-certification audit
- Quality Assurance and Control Activities, Statistical Process Control (SPC)
- Production Planning and Control (Supply Chain Management) Resources, Machinery, Raw & packing material
- Operations Management including recruitment, training and personnel management
- Market watch and strategic planning
- Design new products and establish manufacturing process
- Plan and Audit Quality Systems
- Vendor development and customer relations

## Skills & Expertise

**Business Process Improvement** 

**Waste Reduction** 

**Productivity Coaching** 

**Business Process Design** 

**Business Transformation** 

**CMMI** 

**Software Project Management** 

**SDLC** 

**Requirements Analysis** 

**Process Consulting** 

**Management Consulting** 

IT Strategy

**Business Process** 

**Business Analysis** 

**Global Delivery** 

**Project Portfolio Management** 

**PMO** 

**Program Management** 

Management

**Consulting** 

**Project Management** 

**Capability Maturity Model Integration (CMMI)** 

#### Education

#### University of Mysore

Master's Degree, Engineering/Industrial Management, 1995 - 1997

Activities and Societies: Water Harvesting, Vertical Space Management, Operations Management

#### University of Mysore

Bachelor's Degree, Electronics and Communication, 1988 - 1992

#### Sharada Vilas High School

High School, General Grooming, 1982 - 1985

Grade: A

Activities and Societies: Scouting - Was a President's Awardee

#### **Interests**

Sahaj Marg/ Heartfulness way of Meditation

Shadow Photography

#### Certifications

#### **Certified Software Test Engineer**

#### **Certified Software Quality Assurance**

ITIL Foundation v1.3

#### **CMMI Assessment Team Member**

### Languages

**English** 

Kannada

Hindi

## Volunteer Experience

#### Traffic Warden at Mysore City Traffic Police

November 2004 - Present

I was volunteering with Mysore City Traffic Police as a Traffic Warden. I was responsible for regulating traffic and support the department during public meetings, strikes, processions and similar situation. I

volunteered for nearly 3 years before I moved to Bangalore. Our services were also utilised during the National Festival Dasara in the Mysore Palace premisis.

## Courses

## **Independent Coursework**

Software Engineering Practicum - By Judy Bamberger

## **Anil Vasista**

Transformation Lead for an Insurance Company at Accenture in India



Contact Anil on LinkedIn